I want to try to answer how similar the
tiny human brains we grow from stems are
to a human baby I hope that helps answer
some of the ethics around enslaving them
to do computation which if you're late
to the show is already happening in this
paper they actually compared them to
human fetuses this paper also kept them
alive for longer than anyone else has
been able to which is 10 months in terms
of their brain activity you can see that
they actually do match the human babies
here it's in black and that starts at 25
weeks because that is the youngest that
a pre-term baby has survived in fact the
longer that they grow them the more
similar that they become other papers
have attempted to figure out how similar
their gene expression really is this was
cited in the same paper and you can see
this is a fetal brain gene expression
and it matches pretty closely to a bunch
of other papers that studied it the
difference is going to be upregulation
of a lot of genes that are associated
with
apoptosis and hypoxia in terms of their
size they can be about 10 mm this is
similar to a human fetus at 8 to 10
weeks of development so even if they are
similar in terms of activity and in
terms of their gene expression they're
quite small but that may change with the
vascularization of these little guys we
can develop a functional vascular system
with the addition of a vascular organoid
the next step is going to be creating
machines that can functionally act as a
heart and they did demonstrate that the
vascular system that they integrated
could hold fluid to answer the question
of how similar they are to a human baby
we created something that we've never
seen before we have brain activity on a
level we've never seen before in a tiny
little neural organoid these structures
are far more complex than we would see
in a mouse's brain for example we don't
know